<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>TIL on Dipak Pawar</title>
    <link>https://dipak-pawar.github.io/tags/til/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TIL on Dipak Pawar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 16:30:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dipak-pawar.github.io/tags/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sparse File</title>
      <link>https://dipak-pawar.github.io/posts/sparse-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dipak-pawar.github.io/posts/sparse-file/</guid>
      <description>Do you know that we can fake the size of file? Yes, you read it correctly. We can fake the size of file. In this article, will focus on sparse files &amp;amp; more details about it.
What&amp;rsquo;s a sparse file? From Wikipedia:
In computer science, a sparse file is a type of computer file that attempts to use file system space more efficiently when the file itself is partially empty. This is achieved by writing brief information (metadata) representing the empty blocks to disk instead of the actual &amp;ldquo;empty&amp;rdquo; space which makes up the block, using less disk space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Partitioning</title>
      <link>https://dipak-pawar.github.io/posts/disk-partitioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 16:30:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dipak-pawar.github.io/posts/disk-partitioning/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Partition? Disk Partitioning allows you to divide hard drive into multiple logical sections. There are several reasons why we do it:
 Multi-boot OS Easier backup Different filesystems to be installed on different partitions Clear separation between operating system and user files  Partitioning Schemes MBR &amp;amp; GPT are two different schemes available to do partitions.
MBR MBR supports maximum four primary partitions. On Linux, one can create more partitions having three primary &amp;amp; one extended partition which may contain multiple logical partitions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
